Total Experience: 2 Year(s) 4 Month(s)

Notice Period: 3 Months

Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Electronics/Telecommunication]

Sharath Chandra N (1) Featured

Software Engineer seeking assignment in Software Development, Software Application Development, Project Management, Requirement Gathering, Python automation, Shell scripting, Data Structures, Data Algorithms, Automation Testing, Software coding, C, Python, JIRA



Current Designation: Software Engineer

Current Company: DSP Group

Current Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Chennai, Hyderabad

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer Industry: Telcom/ISP

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Software Engineer, Software Developer, Software Development, Project Management, Requirement Gathering, Python automation, Shell scripting, Data Structures, Data Algorithms, Automation

Testing, Software coding, C, Python, JIRA, GIT

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 21-Jan-21 Last Modified: 21-Jan-21

Summary

Software Engineer with experience in Python automation framework development for audio quality measurement, performance measurement and validation of SDK. Experience in Developing application with C for FXS/FXO events and audio detection used for automation testing, coding for I2C, SPI.

Work Experience

DSP Group as Software Engineer

Jul 2018 to Till Date

Software Engineer - 07/2019 to present

DSP Group, Bangalore

- Developed a Linux userspace application for detection of Analog phone events from Sangoma's FXS/FXO PCIe card to capture audio for analyzing and comparison of rx and tx using python.
- Automation using Python for performance measurement of VoIP device under test with performance measurement, Audio Quality, network jitter, number of call instances supported.
- Automating the test process for Validating the SDK and its new integrated application features.
- Debugging and coding for I2C, SPI communication interfaces.

Project Trainee Engineer - 07/2018 to 06/2019

DSP Group, Bangalore

- Automation using Python for SIP Dialogue to establish VoIP call between two endpoints.
- Audio quality measurement of call, RTP Packet parsing for payload detection.
- Developed a shell script to create a bridge between WIFI and Ethernet on Raspberry Pi which also runs Kamailio SIP server and DHCP server used in 'CES' Demo.

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Electronics/Telecommunication) from Jawaharlal Nehru Technological University (CMRTC), Hyderabad in 2018

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
C, Python			
scipy, numpy,wave, paramiko, selenium			
ROBOT FRAMEWORK			
Salae logic analyser, Trace32, GIT, JIRA			

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Proficient			

Affirmative Action

Physically Challenged: No

Work Authorization

Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time